{
  "react": [
    {
      "question": "Which of the following valid component return type of React ?",
      "a": "State & Props",
      "b": "Service & Components",
      "c": "State & Services",
      "d": "State & Component",
      "answer": "a"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is true regarding Babel ?",
      "a": "Compiler",
      "b": "Transpilar",
      "c": "Both of the above",
      "d": "None of the above",
      "answer": "a"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is true about key props ?",
      "a": "'Key' props are used to look beauty",
      "b": "'Key' props is a way to identify the newly added element",
      "c": "It is one type of attribute of HTML",
      "d": "It is not used in the array",
      "answer": "b"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the best definition of React.js ?",
      "a": "Server-side Framework",
      "b": "User-interface framework",
      "c": "A Library for building interaction interfaces",
      "d": "None of These",
      "answer": "c"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the children prop ?",
      "a": "A Property that lets you nest components in other components",
      "b": "A Property that adds child values to state",
      "c": "A Property that lets you pass data to child components",
      "d": "A Property that lets you set an object as a property",
      "answer": "a"
    },
    {
      "question": "How can you optimize performance for a function component that aways render the same way ?",
      "a": "Use the useReducer Hook",
      "b": "Use the useMemo Hook",
      "c": "Use the shouldComponentUpdate lifecycle method",
      "d": "Wrap it in the React.memo higher-order component",
      "answer": "d"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is a common use case for ref ?",
      "a": "To directly access a DOM node",
      "b": "To refer to another JavaScript file",
      "c": "To refer to a function",
      "d": "To bind the Function",
      "answer": "a"
    },
    {
      "question": "React separates the user interface into components. How are components combinded to create a user interface ?",
      "a": "With code splitting",
      "b": "By putting them in a folder structure",
      "c": "With webpack",
      "d": "By nesting components",
      "answer": "d"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is NOT a rule for React Hooks ?",
      "a": "Hooks cannot be conditional",
      "b": "Hooks can only be called inside React Function components",
      "c": "Hooks can only be called at the top level of a component",
      "d": "Hooks can be called in Class or Function components",
      "answer": "d"
    },
    {
      "question": "Why should you avoid copying the values of props into a component's state ?",
      "a": "Because that would create two instances of the same state that could become out of sync",
      "b": "Because you want to allow data to flow back up to the parent",
      "c": "Because prop values cannot be stored in state",
      "d": "Because you should never mutate state",
      "answer": "a"
    },
    {
      "question": "",
      "a": "",
      "b": "",
      "c": "",
      "d": "",
      "answer": ""
    }
  ],

  "javascript" : [
    {
      "question": "JavaScript is a ___-side programming language",
      "a": "Client",
      "b": "Server",
      "c": "Both",
      "d": "None",
      "answer": "c"
    },
    {
      "question": "Whick built-in method combines the text of two strings and returns a new string ?",
      "a": "append( )",
      "b": "concat( )",
      "c": "attach( )",
      "d": "None of the above",
      "answer": "b"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is true about cookie handling in JS ?",
      "a": "JavaScript can manipulate cookies using the cookie property of the Document object",
      "b": "JavaScript can read, create, modify, and delete the cookie or cookies that apply to the current web page",
      "c": "Both of the above",
      "d": "None of the above",
      "answer": "c"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which built-in method reverses the order of the elements of an array ?",
      "a": "changeOrder(order)",
      "b": "reverse( )",
      "c": "sort(order)",
      "d": "None of the above",
      "answer": "b"
    },
    {
      "question": "Upon encountering empty statements, what does the JavaScript interpreter do ?",
      "a": "Throws an error",
      "b": "Ignores the statements",
      "c": "Gives a warning",
      "d": "None of the above",
      "answer": "b"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the use of the <noscript> tag in JS ?",
      "a": "The contents are displayed by non-JS-based browsers",
      "b": "Clears all the cookies and cache",
      "c": "Both A and B",
      "d": "None of the above",
      "answer": "a"
    },
    {
      "question": "What does the JS 'debugger' statement do ?",
      "a": "It will debug all the errors in the program at runtime",
      "b": "It acts as a breakpoint in a program",
      "c": "It will debug error in the current statement if any",
      "d": "All of the above",
      "answer": "b"
    },
    {
      "question": "What does the 'toLocaleString( )' method do in JS ?",
      "a": "Returns a localised object representation",
      "b": "Returns a parsed string",
      "c": "Returns a localized string representation of an object",
      "d": "None of the above",
      "answer": "c"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following are closures in JS ?",
      "a": "Variables",
      "b": "Functions",
      "c": "Objects",
      "d": "All of the above",
      "answer": "d"
    },
    {
      "question": "What does ... operator do in JS ?",
      "a": "It is used to spread iterables to individual elements",
      "b": "It is used to describe a datatype of undefined size",
      "c": "No such operator exists",
      "d": "None of the above",
      "answer": "a"
    },
    {
      "question": "",
      "a": "",
      "b": "",
      "c": "",
      "d": "",
      "answer": ""
    }
  ]
}  